Neon is a thriller, fantasy, romance film directed by Mark J. Blackman.
A man is forbidden by higher powers from pursuing love, so he plans to end
his life and finally escape his heartbreaking existence.
Elias, played by Joe Absolom.
Mary, played by Kerry Bennett.
Abner, played by Bill Hutchens.
Longbaugh, played by Fraser James.
Supervisor, played by Ceejay Sargent.
Parker, played by James Kermack.
This is a list of films originally produced and/or distributed theatrically by the
American independent film production and distribution company Neon.
The company was founded in 2017 by CEO Tom Quinn and Tim League; the latter
is also the co-founder of the Alamo Drafthouse Cinema chain.
Its first film, Colossal, was released on April 7, 2017.
Additionally, Neon has acquired the distribution rights to six consecutive Palme d'Or winners at the Cannes Film Festival: Parasite
(2019), Titane (2021), Triangle of Sadness (2022), Anatomy of a Fall (2023), Anora (2024), and It Was Just an Accident (2025).
Parasite is Neon's highest-grossing film with more than $200 million at the box office,
and the distributor first film to win the Academy Award for Best Picture.
While Anora was Neon's second film to win Best Picture.
During 2017 and 2022, Neon's division Super LTD released fourteen films,
mainly focused on international productions and documentaries.
Its last released film was The Quiet Girl (2022), which was nominated for
the Academy Award for Best International Feature Film.
The tone is emotional and intense.